<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Keehun Nam</title>
    <link>https://www.keehun.dev/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Keehun Nam</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2019 08:08:55 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.keehun.dev/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How (Programming) Languages Shape Problem Solving</title>
      <link>https://www.keehun.dev/how-programming-languages-shape-problem-solving/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2019 08:08:55 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.keehun.dev/how-programming-languages-shape-problem-solving/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It is increasingly important to be a multilingual developer. Being a developer who is fluent in many programming languages not only helps your marketability, but it will also improve your problem-solving skills. It will help you become a more powerful developer who can tackle a problem with deeper insight, better-informed architectural decisions, and think beyond the inherent limitations of any single language. In the past six months,&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Practical Dynamic Type Part 3: Attributed Strings</title>
      <link>https://www.keehun.dev/practical-dynamic-type-part-3-attributed-strings/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2019 20:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.keehun.dev/practical-dynamic-type-part-3-attributed-strings/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ensuring that applications remain accessible for all is one of our highest priorities at &lt;a href=&#34;https://livefront.com&#34;&gt;Livefront&lt;/a&gt;, and we believe that a key component in achieving that goal is to flawlessly support Dynamic Type in all of our applications. &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/livefront/practical-dynamic-type-d2b5774e8a8a&#34;&gt;Part 1&lt;/a&gt; of our &lt;em&gt;Practical Dynamic Type&lt;/em&gt; series focused on supporting iOS 10 and &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/livefront/practical-dynamic-type-part-2-testing-613bb845f26b&#34;&gt;Part 2&lt;/a&gt; focused on unit testing. This third installment will focus on Attributed Strings.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Swift&#39;s Characterset</title>
      <link>https://www.keehun.dev/understanding-swifts-characterset/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jan 2019 19:29:33 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.keehun.dev/understanding-swifts-characterset/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Have you ever needed to check if a string was made up only of digits? How about the presence of punctuation or non-alphanumeric characters? One could use a variety of methods from one of the &lt;code&gt;Formatter&lt;/code&gt; classes to &lt;code&gt;NSScanner&lt;/code&gt; to even &lt;code&gt;NSPredicate&lt;/code&gt;, but the &lt;a href=&#34;https://stackoverflow.com/questions/34354740/how-do-you-confirm-a-string-only-contains-numbers-in-swift/34354943&#34;&gt;most&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://stackoverflow.com/questions/34587094/how-to-check-if-text-contains-only-numbers/34587234&#34;&gt;likely&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/swift/comments/40jj5r/is_there_a_way_to_find_whether_or_not_a_character/cyun9yn/&#34;&gt;snippet&lt;/a&gt; you would&#39;ve found involved the use of an inverted &lt;code&gt;CharacterSet&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact Me</title>
      <link>https://www.keehun.dev/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2019 19:38:56 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.keehun.dev/contact/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://www.keehun.dev/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Jan 2019 19:26:16 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.keehun.dev/about/</guid>
      <description>I am currently an Engineer at Crowdstrike where I help stop breaches for the world&#39;s biggest corporations, non-profits, and governments.
I am also the Artistic Director of the Southeast Minnesota Youth Orchestras in Rochester, MN. In addition, I am working with some of my best friends on creating refreshing, authentic concerts of contemporary music connecting audiences with composers at un/pitched.
I am committed to helping devoted individuals get better at both classical music and programming.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Practical Dynamic Type: Part 2, Testing</title>
      <link>https://www.keehun.dev/practical-dynamic-type-part-2-testing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Aug 2018 20:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.keehun.dev/practical-dynamic-type-part-2-testing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last year, &lt;a href=&#34;https://livefront.com&#34;&gt;Livefront&lt;/a&gt;&amp;lsquo;s software developer &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@chris_91497&#34;&gt;Chris Sessions&lt;/a&gt; wrote a &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/livefront/practical-dynamic-type-d2b5774e8a8a&#34;&gt;helpful article&lt;/a&gt; about practical usage of Dynamic Type. This short follow-up addresses one primary concern: &lt;em&gt;Unit Testing&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Program Note for Shostakovich&#39;s Symphony No. 10</title>
      <link>https://www.keehun.dev/musical/program-note-for-shostakovich-s-symphony-no.-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Nov 2017 16:25:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.keehun.dev/musical/program-note-for-shostakovich-s-symphony-no.-10/</guid>
      <description>The Tenth Symphony marked a big return for Dmitri Shostakovich, who had been suffering from a denunciation by the Soviet government, whose officials were against all music, art, and literature that they considered too abstract, formal, and serious. Along with Sergei Prokofiev, Aram Khachaturian, and other artists, Shostakovich was denounced in 1948 for writing “non-Russian” music. He had already been denounced once before in 1936 from which he recovered by composing his Fifth Symphony.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Program Notes: Symphony No. 1 by Brahms</title>
      <link>https://www.keehun.dev/musical/brahms-1-program-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Oct 2017 10:22:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.keehun.dev/musical/brahms-1-program-notes/</guid>
      <description>Many contemporaries of Brahms considered him to be the true successor to Beethoven. Because of this lineage, Brahms faced extremely high, if not unrealistic, expectations for his First Symphony. It would be on the basis of this symphony that many judged whether or not Brahms was the true successor of Beethoven. Who could manage to follow the Ninth Symphony’s grand musical gestures, its infinite horizon of musical depth, and its epic hope for joy and unity among the brotherhood of Mankind?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Program Notes for February 5, 2017</title>
      <link>https://www.keehun.dev/musical/program-notes-for-february-5-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2017 12:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.keehun.dev/musical/program-notes-for-february-5-2017/</guid>
      <description>Program notes written for Ithaca College Symphony Orchestra&#39;s concert on February 5, 2017.
Piano Concerto in A minor, op. 16 (Grieg) Grieg was only 24 years-old when he composed this concerto—the only concerto he completed in his life. It was premiered in Copenhagen on April 3, 1869, and a months later, it was premiered in his own country in Oslo, Norway. Like many composers before him, Grieg never quite finished the work, revising it throughout his career until he died.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Beethoven Myth: An Annotated Bibliography</title>
      <link>https://www.keehun.dev/musical/annotated-bibliography-on-the-beethoven-myth/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2016 12:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.keehun.dev/musical/annotated-bibliography-on-the-beethoven-myth/</guid>
      <description>Many years ago, Beethoven ceased being a man and became an icon—a legendary symbol of genius. This transformation began even when Beethoven was alive and is the product of the Westernized cultures with which Beethoven shared his music. Our reverence for this man goes beyond his works and extends well beyond his human qualities. Since his death, he has been called &amp;quot;the man who freed music,&amp;quot; the man whose voice has been lent to the hopes of oppressed people all over the world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Program Notes for November 17, 2016</title>
      <link>https://www.keehun.dev/musical/program-notes-for-november-17-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2016 12:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.keehun.dev/musical/program-notes-for-november-17-2016/</guid>
      <description>Program notes written for Ithaca College Sinfonietta&#39;s concert on February 5, 2017.
Polovtsian Dances Alexander Borodin is one of the most interesting composers. He was not only a widely respected organic chemist in his day (he is co-credited with the discovery of the Aldol reaction) but he also composed one of the most famous Russian operas (Prince Igor), adopted children, and was an activist for women’s rights (especially in equal education).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Program Notes for April 2, 2016</title>
      <link>https://www.keehun.dev/musical/program-notes-for-april-2-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Mar 2016 16:12:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.keehun.dev/musical/program-notes-for-april-2-2016/</guid>
      <description>Program notes written for Vanderbilt Commodore Orchestra&#39;s concert on April 2, 2016.
Semiramide (1823) While it’s accepted that many old tales have become inconsistent over the years, Semiramis is in her own class when it comes to the sheer number and diversity of variations. The version Rossini chose to write about in his last Italian opera comes from Voltaire’s tragedy Semiramis.
There are threads of consistency among the plethora of different versions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Program Notes for January 30, 2016</title>
      <link>https://www.keehun.dev/musical/program-notes-for-january-30-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2016 16:57:32 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.keehun.dev/musical/program-notes-for-january-30-2016/</guid>
      <description>Program notes written for Vanderbilt Commodore Orchestra&#39;s concert on January 30, 2016.
Polovtsian Dances Alexander Borodin is one of the most interesting composers. He was not only a widely respected organic chemist in his day (he is co-credited with the discovery of the Aldol reaction) but he also composed one of the most famous Russian operas (Prince Igor), adopted children, and was an activist for women’s rights (especially in equal education).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Program Notes for February 22, 2015</title>
      <link>https://www.keehun.dev/musical/program-notes-for-february-22-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2015 16:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.keehun.dev/musical/program-notes-for-february-22-2015/</guid>
      <description>Program notes written for Vanderbilt Commodore Orchestra&#39;s concert on February 22, 2015.
Debussy: Prelude to the Afternoon of a Faun Prelude to the Afternoon of a Faun is one of Debussy’s most revolutionary pieces. Pierre Boulez said of the piece that it “brought new breath to the art of music.” Debussy said of his own work that:
Although Mallarmé was against Debussy’s setting of his poem on principle (words were perfect on their own), he wrote the following to Debussy after hearing it at a concert:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to the Introduction of Musical Rhetoric</title>
      <link>https://www.keehun.dev/musical/introduction-to-the-introduction-of-musical-rhetoric/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2014 18:04:20 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.keehun.dev/musical/introduction-to-the-introduction-of-musical-rhetoric/</guid>
      <description>Introduction The skill of rhetoric and the pursuit to achieve it has been one of the most coveted in all of recorded human history perhaps only secondary to the pursuit of love and happiness, or to find the meaning of life. From every powerful men who have conquered various corners of the earth to the witches who have seduced them, rhetoric has been at the core of their success. If it wasn’t for the idea and the study of rhetoric, the Socratic Dialogues or Homer’s Iliad may have no influence on us today, and the geo-political boundaries may look completely different.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Relevance of Philosophy for a Musician</title>
      <link>https://www.keehun.dev/musical/the-relevance-of-philosophy-for-a-musician/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2014 11:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.keehun.dev/musical/the-relevance-of-philosophy-for-a-musician/</guid>
      <description>This essay is the written corroboration of the self-transformative process regarding my views on abstract branches of Philosophy such as metaphysics and ontology. So far, I have ignorantly dismissed them as irrelevant. However, taking this course on Continental Philosophy has taught me that it is not as irrelevant as it initially seems. This essay, in its current form, reflects the status of my thought at the time of my writing. The essay acted as the whiteboard of my constantly evolving ideas about various issues in music, art, and aesthetics, and what you see are only the surviving remnants.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spring 2014 Concerts!</title>
      <link>https://www.keehun.dev/musical/spring-2014-concerts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2013 16:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.keehun.dev/musical/spring-2014-concerts/</guid>
      <description>I am conducting an entire concert of my own this February and have another in April with Grammy-nominated violinist Peter Shepperd Skærved!
 The Commodore: An Introduction to Cornelius Vanderbilt February 22, 2014 at 03:00pm in Ingram Hall
 The brand-new Vanderbilt Commodore Orchestra celebrates its inaugural concert by getting to know the man who not only gave the Commodores their name but was also one of the most influential men in all of American history.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Handel&#39;s Trumpet Sonata</title>
      <link>https://www.keehun.dev/musical/handels-trumpet-sonata/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2012 06:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.keehun.dev/musical/handels-trumpet-sonata/</guid>
      <description>With the recent passing of Supreme Court&#39;s decision to allow re-copyrighting of Public Domain works, Congress will pass a legislation that will implement just that&amp;ndash;in order to satisfy their lobbyists&amp;rsquo; deep pockets. This is the single worst decision and piece of legislation I&#39;ve ever came across. It is more ridiculous than SOPA or PIPA.
In a form of protest, I am releasing a piece of music that should be in the Public Domain by now.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>